# **Charles Tucker Barrett**

ctbarrett.tech@gmail.com | 919-999-7792 | Raleigh, NC | 27540

Website: https://tucker.tech

GitHub: https://github.com/GrinninBarrett | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tucker-barrett

### Summary

Full stack web developer with a background in music education. Experienced working on collaborative teams, spontaneous problem-solving, and devising creative approaches to difficult situations. Interested in leveraging my technical and artistic experience to solve real-world problems to make our planet a better place. Possess a Full Stack Web Development certificate and have a genuine love for technology and the arts.

## **Technical Skills**

Git/GitHub, Agile, JavaScript, MongoDB, Express, React, Redux, Node.js, GraphQL, MySQL, JSON, HTML, CSS

# **Projects**

**CoinBull** | Contributing Developer | https://coinbullapp.herokuapp.com/

- ◆ Full stack web application to track cryptocurrency information | MERN stack, GraphQL, Heroku
- ♦ Repo: https://github.com/GrinninBarrett/CoinBull

Book Search Engine | Sole Developer | https://glacial-stream-35332.herokuapp.com/

- ◆ Full stack web application to search for and save books | MERN stack, GraphQL, Heroku
- ♦ Repo: https://github.com/GrinninBarrett/book-search-engine

Skillet & Shaker | Contributing Developer | https://grinninbarrett.github.io/recipe-finder

- ♦ Uses recipe APIs to find food and drink recipes based on user criteria | JavaScript, HTML, and CSS
- Repo: https://github.com/grinninbarrett/recipe-finder

**Etch-a-Sketch** | Sole Developer | https://grinninbarrett.github.io/etch-a-sketch

- ◆ Drawing canvas based on the famous Etch-a-Sketch | JavaScript, HTML, and CSS
- ◆ Repo: https://github.com/grinninbarrett/etch-a-sketch

## Experience

Full Stack Boot Camp Teaching Assistant / Central Grader - 2U - (February 2022 - present)

- ♦ Guide students in their learning of web development technologies and practices
- Evaluate the quality of student assignment submissions; provide detailed feedback for students' growth

Specialist - Apple - (October 2021 - present)

♦ Utilize thorough product knowledge to provide personalized solutions for new Apple product owners

ESL Teacher - VIPKid - (2018 - 2022)

- ♦ Maintained a nearly 100% rebooking rate 100% 5/5 star-rated teacher
- Managed relationships with students and parents, built strong rapport

Music Teacher - South Harnett Elementary School, Bunnlevel, NC - (2019 - 2021)

- ♦ Developed a comprehensive, sequential music curriculum for grades 3-5 and K-5 special needs
- ♦ Planned and executed successful performances, ensuring students' personal and musical growth

Kindergarten/ESL Teacher - Worwick Franklin Institute, Ulsan, South Korea - (2015 - 2018)

- ♦ Contributed to a nearly 200% increase in enrollment after my first year
- Bridged language and cultural divides to collaborate with Korean coworkers

#### Certificates

- ♦ Introduction to Computer Science and Programming Using Python, MITx
- ♦ Responsive Web Design, freeCodeCamp

#### Education

University of North Carolina - Chapel Hill, Chapel Hill, NC - 2021

Certificate - JavaScript Full Stack Web Development

University of South Carolina, Columbia, SC - 2012

Bachelor of Music Education with Horn Performance Certificate